# **David Cha**

Flushing, NY 11354 | 929-394-9440 | david.cha44@gmail.cuny.edu GitHub | Medium | LinkedIn

## **Full Stack Software Engineer**

Experienced Web Developer in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in Economics, Education, and Hospitality. Possess strong skills in team-building, communicating efficiently, and bringing positive energy to the team morale. Bilingual in English and Korean.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, CSS, HTML

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Y.A.M.S - Frontend | Backend

Web app guide users towards the best food based on their location

- Implemented Fusion Yelp API to list the surrounding restaurants near the user
- Utilized the Mapbox API to show where the user is and to target all the restaurant's locations with React
- Constructed a user profile where they can sign-in and look at their go-to-list of restaurants as well as a log-out
- Designed it to be mobile friendly, to improve user interaction

# Yap Station - Frontend | Backend

Collaborated project. Web app allows users to post status, comments, and photos

- Implemented Carrier Wave to implement photo, posts, and video posts
- Constructed a user profile where they can sign-in and look at their feeds and posts
- Designed the web app with bootstrap and CSS

## Car Deets - Frontend | Backend

Web app allows users choosing the right car for the individual and taking a closer look at the specifications

- Implemented Vanilla JavaScript to fabricate a simple frontend and to create a more user-friendly app
- Created accurate seed data with Ruby Rails to produce numerous vehicles
- Developed a Ruby backend that has a three model relationship with the user, the car, and comments as the joiner
- Utilized CSS to design the layout of the frontend

#### **EXPERIENCE**

O-Toro Inc. New York, NY 9/2017 - 10/2019

Operational Manager

- Increased Company delivery output by 10% by constructing a consistent driving routine as a solution to increase client(s) satisfaction.
- Maintained 95% clients satisfaction rate by mediating tensions between the company and clients.
- Managed the company's sale transactions to create a more organized file structure and increased the company's efficiency by 5%.

## The Child Center of New York at I.S 237

New York, NY

After School Teacher/Assistant Basketball Coach

10/2015 - 6/2016

- Constructed lesson plans and taught fundamentals of the core concepts to 20 student participants.
- Built stable connections with students and co-workers which gave rise to 25% in positive communication.
- Tutored algebra to sixth, seventh, and eighth graders and helped them complete 100% of their homeworks.

## (USTA) United States Tennis Association

New York, NY 6/2014 - 9/2014

**Assistant Coach** 

- Participated in the yearly world tournament by assisting player participants, sped up the tournament process by 5%.
- Assisted the coach by managing 40% of the class with exercise and drills which involved every student in the class.
- Focused on solidifying students features which helped 8 students to progress up to the next class.

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Dumbo, NY 12/2019 - 4/2020 Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

**Queens College** Flushing, NY Bachelors in Economics 5/2018